this video is sponsored by app
cloud test their servers with
storage faster than any
ssd for free and get $25
credit with the promo code
beta t hey guys and welcome to
another day of beta take for those of you new
to the channel here we talk about software and
technology and specifically in this
series we talk about design patterns
we are going to explain each design pattern one by one
looking at the utilities and
explaining them with examples if you still don't
know what a design pattern is I'll
leave the index of the series
up here and in the description in
today's video we are going to talk about the
corrector pattern the collector pattern is a
structural pattern that allows us to
extend the functionalities of a class
without having to resort to inheritance
when you have an object and you want to
add functionality to it it's very easy to
fall into the temptation of implementing a
super complex class hierarchy by
creating classes for each
possible combination of elements for
example imagine that we are
developing a game where our
enemies have power apps we have
normal enemies and enemies that wear
certain items that give them certain
properties
these enemies can put on armor
which  it modifies behaviors such as
the way they move and the way they
defend themselves then at some moments they
can even wear a helmet which
makes them resistant to direct attacks to the
head the thing is in summary that all
the enemies in the game can have
these varieties so if we
wanted to organize them
simply using inheritance we would end up
having a class for the enemy one
for the enemy with a helmet another for the
enemy with armor another for the
enemy with armor and helmet etcetera
for all the different enemies
that exist in our game and imagine
then if we want to have a new type
of clothing I don't know gloves this is
a problem that mistreated causes an
explosion of classes that ends up being
unmaintainable with the collector pattern
we get an elegant solution to be
able to generate these objects
dynamically without having to define all the
possible combinations statically
composition versus inheritance we could
think that we can solve this
for example with strategy and with a
strategic pattern but that pattern would
also generate
a large number of classes since we
would have to make a strategy for
each possible combination the
corrector pattern allows us to solve this
let's see how it does it the
corrector pattern allows us to extend
behaviors dynamically which is
precisely what  what we want to achieve let's
consider as base behavior the
behavior of an enemy without any
extra then we create each
decorator separately the intention is to
have decorators such as
armor or helmet to be
able to combine them freely on
any enemy, that is to say a
base enemy with an armor decorator
would have a modified behavior to
one that doesn't have it and we also want to
add decorators not only to
base enemies but also to enemies with other
decorators for example adding a helmet to
an enemy that already has armor
we want to create a
layered organization as if it were an onion where we
can dynamically add layers to the enemy
to modify its
behavior let's first define
the nomenclature of the parts of the pattern
to make it easier to understand
our base character
would be the component that we want to decorate
and we want to be able to do it with
arbitrary sets of these decorators now
let's see the idea that allows us to
bring this layered structure to reality
without breaking anything because I
tell you the truth reading this it seemed like a
bit of black magic the idea is that a
decorator is also a component, that is to
say from the outside it doesn't matter to us if we
have an undecorated component like
the base enemy or a decorated component
like  the enemy with armor we want to be
able to treat them equally so a
decorator has to be a component
in order to be treated as a
component a decorator has to
inherit from component in addition to this a
decorator is not only a component but
has a component inside this is
precisely what allows us to have
layers and to be able to combine different
effects from different decorators if we
want to have an enemy with armor and
helmet we create the helmet decorator which will
have a component inside this
component that has inside is a
decorator with the armor and this
decorator with armor in turn has
another one inside
which is the base enemy if we look at the
complete onion we get the enemy
that wears armor and wears a helmet and the
fact that a decorator can
behave like a component in a
polymorphic way allows us to abstract from
what we have inside we have a
component inside but this component
can be an already decorated component and
this can grow and have layers and
layers and layers and layers that in the end you
treat it equally
let's see how
the classes would be organized with the example of the
enemies but before continuing let me
thank the sponsor of
this video up close up cloud is a
solution of  hosting that offers the
fastest servers on the market
offer both an app and a
super intuitive yet very
powerful control panel that allows you to automate the
scalability of your products. In addition,
all their servers have
maxi or ps technology that offers
faster disk speeds than
any ssd. You can try app cloud for
free using the beta
tec code that I leave the description and you will
receive $ 25 of credit to
use on the platform. Continuing with
the example we would
have our component that would be
the enemy this component would be an
abstraction of all our enemies
so each specific enemy would
inherit from this abstraction then we
would have the abstraction of the
decorators this generic decorator
would have an attribute of type component and would
also inherit from the same definition
of component if you notice it is a
recursive architecture where a
component ends up having components
within this form as I have said
we can add the layers the
base enemy would be the component that
is inside the decorator and since the
decorator is in turn a component each
message it receives from the outside it can
transmit it to the internal component because
in the end it uses the same interface in
this way the messages  they can be
sending to increasingly internal layers
until reaching the base enemy and you
can also modify the
behaviors as the message
goes through these layers obviously
each specific type of decorator would
inherit from the base class so for
example we would have the decorators with
helmet and with armor and now comes the
question of how the hell do we mount this from the
outside as useful let's
be a decorated element the idea is
that you have to pass to each decorator through a
constructor the component that you want to
have inside you pass the component
that you want to decorate
therefore you can add decorators
by layers or configure the layers of an
element as follows it would be
within the functions that
the decorator has for being a component
where it would modify the behavior
of the internal component you can even not
depend on the result of the
lower levels and say hey this decorator
overwrites all the logic of the
layers that exist below for example in
the case of the decorator with helmet we
could make it so that if the attack is to the
head the damage becomes zero and
therefore it makes no sense to transmit the
message of I have been damaged to the
lower layers because the decorator itself will
say I have been damaged but not  it
affects because I wear a helmet in the end one
thing to keep in mind when using
this pattern is that the order in which
the decorators are added can end up
influencing the final result if a
decorator has the behavior for
example of living the damage by two it depends
on which layer you put it it can modify
the total damage or only
the partial damage which is why
this pattern is used keep in mind that the order
has relevance in the behavior and
basically how our
class structure would look at the end would be something
like this with this architecture we have
defined all the possible types of
enemy combining their power apps without
falling into an explosion of classes also
adding a new power up would imply the
creation of a single new class which
greatly facilitates the extension of the
system I hope you liked this video
if it has been so please do not
forget to subscribe and give it a like and
leave me in the comments what pattern
you want us to analyze in the next
video see you in the next video
bye